Guide to the Stanford Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts Recordings
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Audiovisual material
  - Audio
    - Garber, Marjorie, January 11, 2001; 4.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
      Marjorie Garber is one of the rare intellectuals whose work has had a significant resonance in both academic and popular culture. Writing on a wide variety of topics, from Shakespeare to "Charlotte's Web," she has demonstrated both a keen analysis of cultural productions and a flair for the intriguing anecdote. In its wide-ranging breadth, her work is most often concerned with the construction of identity in a particular societal context-particularly by minority groups within a given society whose difference from received norms challenges that society's implicit assumptions about its members' identity. Indeed, she is most well known for her work on gender identity, particularly in her ground-breaking Vested Interests: Cross-dressing and Cultural Anxiety (1992), which examines transvestitism in a number of contexts in Western culture and cultural productions. Here, as elsewhere, the conclusions she draws have consequences that reach beyond the confines of the academy: it is not surprising that her work has found an audience in activists and public intellectuals as well as in scholars. Currently, Garber is the William R. Kenan Jr. Professor of English and Director of the Center for Literary and Cultural Studies at Harvard University. She spoke at Stanford on Monday, January 11, 2000, at 7 p.m. in the Law School.
    - Latour, Bruno, "Why has critical spirit run out of steam? About Iconoclash and beyond", 2003 Apr 7; 2 optical disc(s) (CD)
    - Hofstadter, Douglas R., discussion, 2006 Feb 7; 4.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    - Gutmann, Amy, "Whitehead's Account of the Sixth Day: A Symposium with: Isabelle Stengers, Donna Haraway, and Richard Rorty.", April 21, 2006; 4.14; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 4)
      CD with audio and video files of both lectures [.mov, .rm and .mp3 files]
      - Whitehead's Account of the Sixth Day: A Symposium with: Isabelle Stengers, Donna Haraway, and Richard Rorty. Extremism:, April 21, 2006; 4.15; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 4)
        CD with audio/video files of both lectures [. rm and .mov files].